너희들 지금이 우리가
싱글로서 만나는
Do you realize this is the last time
we'll be here...
마지막이란 거 알아?
as six single people?
왜? 커피숍 문 닫아?
What's happening to the coffeehouse?
지금부터, 너희들과
나와 내 색시지
From now on, it's you four
and me and the missus.
귀여운 여자, 아내
오래된 구속 장치
The little woman. The wife.
The old ball and chain.
- 오래되다니?
- 아니 새 구속 장치
-Old?
-The young, hot ball and chain.
- 훨 낫다
- 가봐야겠다
-Much better.
-We gotta go.
- 어딜?
- 드레스 찾고 엄마랑 점심 먹어
-Where?
-Get the dress and lunch with mom.
조이, 너도?
Joey, you too?
난 "점심"소리가 들리길래
I just heard "lunch."
나도 가지 뭐
Yeah, I can go. Sure.
다들 가서 잘 됐다
Actually, I'm glad they're leaving.
너한테 할 얘기가
있었거든
I need to talk to you
about something.
- 뭔데?
- 좀 어색하긴 한데
-What's up?
-This may be a little awkward.
돈 빌릴 거라면 때가 안 좋아
내일 128명의 저녁을 사거든
If you need money, it's a bad time.
I'm buying 128 dinners tomorrow.
그런 게 아니야
No, it's not that.
이건 네 친구로서가 아니라
I'm not gonna say this
as your friend...
모니카의 오빠로 하는 얘기야
but as Monica's older brother.
- 그래도 내 친구지?
- 지금은 아냐
-But you're still my friend?
-Not for a few minutes.
- 그럼 내 들러리는?
- 아냐
-Right now, are you still my best man?
-No.
로스라고 불러도 돼?
Do I still call you Ross?
둘이 결혼하게 돼서
말할 수 없이 기쁘지만
You guys are getting married,
and I couldn't be more thrilled.
모니카 오빠로서
이 말은 해야겠어
But as her older brother,
I have to tell you this:
내 동생을 아프게 하거나
If you ever hurt my little sister...
조금이라고 불행하게
하는 날에는
if you ever cause her
any unhappiness of any kind...
지구 끝까지라고 쫓아가서
I will hunt you down...
손을 봐 줄 거야
and kick your ass.
왜 그래? 난 심각한데
What? I'm serious.
- 웃지 마! 농담 아냐
- 무슨 말인지 알겠고
-Dude! Stop it! I'm not kidding.
-I hear what you're saying...
경고해줘서 고마워
and thanks for the warning.
괜찮아
No problem.
우리 다시 친구야?
Are we friends again?
그래
Yeah.
방금 모니카 오빠가
나한테 뭐랬는지 알아?
You won't believe what Monica's
brother just said to me!
The One With Monica and
Chandler's Wedding
The One With Monica and Chandler's Wedding
뭐해, 모니카?
What you doing, Mon?
결혼식 때 잘못될 일
목록쓰고 있어
I'm listing things that
could go wrong at the wedding.
마음의 준비를 하게
So I can be prepared.
- 어떤 거?
- "드레스 안 찾아왔다"
-What are they?
-"The dresses won't get picked up...
"베일을 잃었다,
파란색 물건이 없다"
veil gets lost,
and I'm missing something blue."
다 내가 할 일이잖아
I'm responsible for all those.
확률대로 가야지
I had to go with the odds.
내가 떨어진 배역 있잖아
Remember I didn't get that part?
- 광고?
- 연극?
-The commercial?
-That play?
다른 연극?
That other play?
- 영화?
- 맞아!
-The movie?
-Yes!
개가 비행기 조종하는
그 영화?
The one about the dog
who flies planes?
아니, 그 생각하면 속 쓰려
No. But man, that one hurt.
- 세계 1차 대전 군인들 얘기야
- 잘 됐다
-This is the one about WWI soldiers.
-Oh, yeah.
당시엔 "대 전쟁"이라고 불렀지
Back then we called it
"The Great War."
It really was.
정말 대단했어
역 맡은 사람이 못 한댔대
오늘부터 촬영이야!
A guy they wanted backed out!
I start shooting today!
축하해!
Congratulations!
- 오늘 리허설하기로 했잖아
- 그 전에 끝나
-Today's the dinner.
-I'll be done by then.
그럼 잘됐다
대 영화배우 탄생하겠네!
Oh. Then way to go,
you big movie star!
이따 봐, 나찌와
싸우러 가야 돼
See you. I'm off
to fight the Nazis.
조이, 나찌와 싸운 건
2차대전이지
Wait, Joey. We fought the Nazis
in WWII, not WWI.
Whoa.
그럼 누구와 싸웠지?
Who was in WWI?
말씀하셔
Go ahead.
늦겠다! 어서 가!
You're gonna be late!
Go! Go!
1차 대전 땐
누구와 싸웠지?
Who did we fight in WWI?
-Mexico?
-Yes. Very good.
- 멕시코 아냐?
- 맞아, 똑똑하네
'피어 59 스튜디오'
- 조이, 준비됐어요
- 네, 나도요
-Hey, Joey. We're ready.
-Yeah, me too.
리차드, 준비됐어요
Richard, we're ready for you.
조이 트리비아니, 빈센트 역을
맡은 리차드 크로스비예요
Joey Tribbiani, Richard Crosby
is playing Vincent.
- 제 상대역이세요?
- 반갑네
-I'm acting with you?
-Nice to meet you.
이럴 수가,
오스카 상 타셨잖아요
I can't believe this. Incredible.
You just won an Oscar.
아닐세
No, I didn't.
타신 것 같은데
I think you did.
아니, 세 번 물 먹었지
I think I lost, three times.
-Cookie? Would you...?
-No.
- 쿠키 좀 드실래요?
- 됐네
촬영 전까지
한 시간 남았으니
We're about an hour away
from getting the scene lit.
- 두 사람 연습 좀 할까요?
- 네, 그러죠
-Can you guys run it a couple times?
-Yeah, sure.
좋아요, 합시다
All right. Let's do it.
액션!
And... action!
- 소대를 찾아야 돼!
- 소대는 가 버렸어!
-We have to find the platoon!
-Forget it, the platoon is gone!
-What?
-Platoon's dead! Face facts, Tony!
- 뭐라고?
- 가버렸다고, 현실을 직시해
What'll we do?
We have no reinforcements or food.
어쩌지? 지원병력도
음식도 떨어졌는데
지하실에 감자와
파스타가 있던데
There's food in the basement.
Potatoes and some pasta.
조이, 왜 자꾸
얼굴을 만지나?
Hang on. Joey, you keep
touching your face.
뭐 문제있나?
Something wrong?
No.
아뇨
인물에 개성을 줄 것
같아서요
I thought it might be
a cool character thing.
얼굴 만지는 사람이죠
He's a face toucher.
마음에 안 들어
I don't think so.
Let's take it back
to Richard's last lines. Action!
리차드 마지막 대사부터
액션!
무기는 없어도
식량은 있잖아
No weapons, but we still have food.
Potatoes, pasta...
감자, 파스타
참치도 몇 캔있고
and a few tins of tuna!
Honey, we gotta go!
자기, 가야 돼!
Here's a question
you never want to ask:
듣고 싶지 않은
질문 하나 해야겠다
아버지가 자기 진주 목걸이
빌릴 수 있냐고 하셔
Can my dad borrow one of your
pearl necklaces?
어떤 옷을 입으실지
말씀하셨어?
Did he say what kind of neckline
he's wearing?
No.
아니
한 번밖에 못 뵀지만
내 생각으론
I just met him once,
but I'm guessing...
plunging?
많이 파진 거?
그래, 뭐든 내 보이길
좋아하시니까
He is more of a if-you've-got-it-
flaunt-it kind of father.
레이첼한테 물어볼게
Let me see if Rachel has anything.
Yes, include more people.
그래, 동네방네 소문내라
내일 이 시간에
결혼한다는 거 믿어져?
Do you realize that tomorrow
we're gonna be getting married?
내일 밤 데이트 있는데
I have a date tomorrow night.
- 우리가 해내다니
- 그게 뭐 대단하다고
-I can't believe we made it.
-Don't sound so surprised.
I'm sorry, but...
미안하지만...
-Nothing.
-What?
- 별 거 아냐
- 뭔데?
Well, honestly?
Ever since we got engaged...
솔직히 말하면
우리 약혼한 후 줄곧
자기가 언제 겁먹나
생각했거든
I've waited for you to flip out.
Honestly? Me too.
솔직히 말하면 나도 그래
- 정말?
- 그럼
-Really?
-Yeah.
무슨 일이 생겨서
내가 바보처럼...
I think that something
will come up and I'll...
챈들러 짓하면
어쩌나하고
go all Chandler.
-But nothing has.
-I'm so glad.
- 아무 일도 없었잖아
- 너무 기뻐
Thank you for staying
so calm during this.
침착하게 있어줘서
고마워
그 덕분에 나도 침착했어
It's made me stay calm.
더 나쁠 수도 있었어
I could've been worse.
금방 따라갈게
I'll be right there.
Before Saturday, you've reached
Monica and Chandler.
토요일 전이면
모니카와 챈들러의 집이고
토요일 후면
빙 부부의 집입니다
But if you're calling after Saturday,
you've reached Mr. and Mrs. Bing.
빙 부부에게
메시지를 남겨주세요!
Please leave a message for...
the Bings!
Maureen!
모린!
- 내 사촌, 모린이야
- 빙 부부입니다
-This is my cousin, Maureen.
-We're the Bings.
너희들 너무 멋지다
Hi! You guys look so beautiful.
빙 부부잖아!
Mr. and Mrs. Bing!
Wow, Monica.
와, 모니카
챈들러한테 내가 오빠로서
한마디 했거든
So you know, I had my
older-brother talk with Chandler.
뭐라고 했는데?
What is that?
너한테 상처주면
I told him that if he ever hurt you...
지옥까지라도 쫓아가
혼내준다고 했지
I would hunt him down
and kick his ass.
너희들 왜 그래?
난 심각한데
What is the matter with everybody?
I'm serious.
정말 혼내줄 거야!
I would kick his ass!
화장 지워진다!
Ross, please, my makeup!
- 챈들러
- 엄마
-Chandler.
-Mom.
뭐든 입고 오셔서 고마워요
Thanks for wearing... something.
못난 부모한테서
이런 날이 올 줄 몰랐다
This is so exciting! I thought we
screwed you up too much for this.
곧 있으면 애들이
바글바글하겠지
Just think, soon there will be
lots of little Bings.
또 가서 침세례를
받아야 한다니까
I can't believe I'm going back
to get spit on again.
너한테 침뱉는 사람은
그래도 유명하잖아
You're lucky, the people
who spit on you are famous.
- 넌 누가 침뱉는데?
- 일 얘긴 하기 싫어
-Who spits on you?
-I don't want to talk about work.
Mrs. Bing? These are my parents,
Judy and Jack Geller.
어머니?
우리 부모님이세요
- 만나서 반가워요
- 아버님, 아님 어머님?
-It's lovely to meet you.
-Are you his mother or father?
여보!
Jack!
뭐? 한 번도 못 봤단 말야
What? I've never seen one before.
저기 오빠한테 가서
얘기 좀 하세요
Dad, there's Ross.
Go talk to him.
아무렇지 않은 척
하려고 했단 말야
I wasn't even able to act
like I'm okay with it.
Hello, all.
얘들아
Hi... Dad.
아버지, 오셨어요?
어서 오세요, 아버님
Hi, Mr. Bing.
- 노라
- 찰스
-Nora.
-Charles.
- 두 분 다 오셔서 기뻐요
- 아무렴
-It's so great to see you both here.
-Yes.
Although we may be seeing
too much of some people.
어떤 사람은 자기
분수를 모르는 것 같군
그런 옷 입기엔
너무 늙지 않았나?
Aren't you too old
to wear a dress like that?
그런 옷 입기엔
거시기가 부끄럽지 않아요?
Don't you have too much penis
to wear a dress like that?
맙소사
Oh, my God.
물론 혼내줄 수 있지
Of course you can kick his ass, son.
넌 맘만 먹으면 누구든
혼내 줄 수 있어
You could kick anyone's ass
you want to.
Thanks, you guys.
고마워요
-Rach, Rach?
-Yeah?
- 레이첼?
- 왜?
챈들러 아버지와 얘기 좀 해
어머니와 떨어져 계시게
Talk to Chandler's dad and
keep him away from Chandler's mom.
- 어떻게 생기셨어?
- 검은 드레스입은 남자
-What's he look like?
-A man in a black dress.
I'm Rachel, a friend of
Monica and Chandler's.
레이첼이에요
신랑, 신부 친구죠
- 아맨다예요
- 아, 알았다
-I'm Amanda.
-Oh, I get it.
"나 남자 다!"
"A man, duh!"
Could I have your attention?
잠시 주목해주세요
- 전 로스 겔러예요
- 로스 겔러 박사지
-I'm Ross Geller.
-Dr. Ross Geller.
Dad, please. As I was saying...
아버진 참...
그래요
전 로스 겔러 박사입니다
I'm Dr. Ross Geller.
신랑의 들러리죠
And I'm the best man.
이 결혼은 제게
두 배로 특별합니다
This marriage
is doubly special for me...
신랑이 제 가장 친한 친구고
because not only is the groom
my best friend...
신부는 제 동생이거든요
but the bride is my little sister.
세상에서 가장 훌륭한
여동생이지요
She's the greatest sister
a guy could ask for.
다들 잔을 들어서
Please join me in raising a glass...
이 예비부부를
축복해줍시다
to the couple we're
here to celebrate.
-To the Bings.
-To the Bings!
- 빙 부부를 위하여
- 빙 부부를 위하여!
I'm gonna steam my dress.
난 드레스 다릴 건데
누가 그 동안
드레스 좀 봐줄래?
Who will make sure nothing
happens to it?
- 내가 할게
- 아무도 없어?
-I'll do it.
-Who wants it? Anybody?
-I said I'll do it.
-Nobody?
- 내가 한다니까
- 아무도 없어?
- 좋아, 내가 하지 뭐
- 나 안 망칠게
-All right, I'll do it myself.
-I'm not gonna screw it up.
You're right. I'm sorry.
You were a big help tonight.
그래, 미안해
오늘도 많이 도와줬는데
할머니 호텔에 모셔다
드린 거 고마워
Thanks for helping
my grandmother get to the hotel.
- 친구 좋다는 게 뭐야
- 그래, 미안해
-Of course! That's what I'm here for.
-Okay. Sorry.
What grandmother?
무슨 할머니?
- 어디 갔다 왔어?
- 부모님 호텔에 데려다 드렸어
-Where have you been?
-Taking my parents to the hotel.
-Going back to work?
-Yeah.
- 일하러 가?
- 응
-Nice shades.
-If I wear these in my scenes...
- 안경 죽인다
- 고마워
이걸 쓰면 눈에는
침이 안 튈 거 아냐
I won't get spit in my eyes.
그래 내 기억으로 '레이벤'이
1차대전 공식 스폰서였지
And, if I remember correctly, Ray-Ban
was the official sponsor of WWI.
Great! All right!
잘 됐네! 좋았어
I'll see you later.
- 나중에 보자
- 그래
-Where's Chandler?
-I think he's in Rachel's room.
- 챈들러 어딨어?
- 레이첼 방에 있을 걸
챈들러?
Chandler?
- 모니카 있어?
- 드레스 다리는데, 왜?
-Is Monica here?
-She's steaming her dress. Why?
- 챈들러가 사라진 것 같아
- 뭐?
-I think Chandler's gone.
-What?
- 이걸 남겼어
- "모니카에게 미안하다고 해줘"
-He left that.
-"Tell Monica I'm sorry."
Oh, my God.
어쩜 좋아
What's up?
왜 그래?
"Tell Monica I'm sorry."
"모니카에게 미안하다고 해줘"
직접 하셔
Tell her yourself.
맙소사
챈들러가 없어졌구나?
Oh, my God.
Chandler just left, though?
아닐 수도 있잖아
Maybe it's not what we think.
"우유 다 마셔서 미안하다고
모니카에서 말해줘"
"Tell Monica I'm sorry
I drank the last of the milk."
아니면 이름을
바꿨을 수도 있잖아
Or maybe he was writing to tell
her that he's changed his name:
"모니카에게 내 이름이
쏘리라고 해줘"
"Tell Monica, I'm Sorry."
- 겁먹고 도망간 것 같아!
- 부정적으로 생각하지 마!
-It means he freaked out and left!
-Don't be so negative!
'쏘리'가 지금 저 안에
있을 가능성도 있잖아
Good God, isn't it possible that
"Sorry" is sitting in there right now?
피비, 로스 말이 맞아
어쩌면 좋지
Phoebe, I think Ross is right.
What are we gonna do?
찾아서 데려와야지
I'm gonna have to go find him
and bring him back.
모니카가
눈치 못 채게 해줘
You make sure Monica
does not find out, okay?
너 만약 찾아서
못 데려오면
But, if you don't find him
and bring him back...
내가 지옥까지 쫓아가
혼내줄 거야!
I am gonna hunt you down
and kick your ass!
찾으면 되잖아
I will find him.
Joey? Can you
go through these lines with me?
조이? 이 대사 연습 좀
같이 할까?
Oh, man, they just re-did my makeup.
방금 분장 새로 했는데
-Just the last two pages.
-All right.
- 마지막 두 장만
- 그러죠
사진을 찾았어!
I found the picture!
사진? 무슨 사진?
Picture? What picture?
내 아내 사진 말야
자네 짐에 있더군
The picture of my wife
I found in your pack.
- 대본 좀 내리겠나?
- 싫은데요
-Could you lower the script?
-I don't want to.
얼굴을 봐야 반응을 보고
연기를 하지
I need to see your face so
I can play off your reaction.
Okay, look.
저기요, 선배님
셰익스피어도 하시고
훌륭한 건 알겠는데
I know you're great
and play all those Shakespeare guys...
얼굴에 침이 마구 튀어요
but you're spitting
all over me, man.
- 당연하지!
- 알고 계셨어요?
-Of course I am!
-You know you've been spitting?
That's what real actors do.
진짜 배우는 다 그런 거야
좋은 배우는 발음이
정확해야돼
Enunciation is the mark
of a good actor.
그럴려면 침이 튀어야지
And when you enunciate, you spit!
Wow. Didn't know that.
와, 몰랐어요
Thanks. Okay, check it out.
고마워요, 보세요
Picture? What picture?
사진? 무슨 사진?
-Have you seen Chandler?
-No, I haven't seen him.
- 챈들러 봤어요?
- 아뇨, 못 봤어요
-Damn.
-He's getting married tomorrow, right?
- 젠장
- 내일 결혼하는 거 맞죠?
네, 걱정마세요
아무 일 없어요
Yes. Don't worry.
Everything's fine.
- 결혼식 때 봐요
- 난 초대 못 받았어요
-See you at the wedding.
-I wasn't invited.
Then we'll see you the
day after tomorrow.
그럼 내일 모레 봐요
엄마? 아버지?
Mom? Dad?
여긴 웬 일이세요?
What are you doing here?
매일 여기 모이길래
뭐가 대단한가 와 봤다
We thought we'd see what
the fuss is all about.
-I see why the girls like coming here.
-Why?
- 여자들이 좋아하는 이윤 알겠다
- 왜요?
저기 섹시한 금발 남자
The sexy blond behind the counter.
-Gunther?
-She just added him to her list.
- 건터요?
- 방금 목록에 올렸다
- 목록이라뇨?
- 같이 잠자고 싶은 사람...
-Your list?
-Of people we're allowed to sleep..
나도 뭔지 알아요
I know what the list is.
Come on, sit down.
Have a cup of joe.
자 앉아서
커피나 한 잔 해
Dad, I can't. I'm sorry.
안 돼요, 죄송해요
If you see Chandler,
tell him I'm looking for him.
챈들러 보면 내가
찾더라고 해 주세요
And if you see Rita Moreno,
let her know I'm looking for her.
리타 모레노 보거든
내가 찾더라고 해 줘
Action!
액션!
I found the picture!
사진을 찾았어!
What picture?
무슨 사진?
A picture of my wife, in your pack!
내 아내 사진 말야
자네 짐에 있더군
You went through my personal property?
내 소지품을 뒤졌어?
Why do you have a picture of Paulette
in your pack?
왜 폴레트 사진이
자네 짐속에 있지?
Because, Vincent, we were lovers...
그건 우린 연인이니까
for two years!
2년 동안이나
Cut! Wonderful!
컷! 좋아요!
잘 하셨어요!
Great scene, huh?
자네도 멋졌어, 마지막
대사할 때 흠뻑 젖었네
You were awesome. In that
last speech, you soaked me.
- 내일 시간표예요
- 내일 안 되는데
-Tomorrow's call sheet.
-I'm not working tomorrow.
- 해야돼요
- 안 돼요, 빼줘요
-You are now.
-No, you gotta get me out of it.
I have plans. Important plans!
중요한 일이 있다고요
-Still no word from Chandler.
-Oh, man.
- 챈들러 소식 없대
- 이를 어째
5번가에서 방황하는
할머닌 찾았대
But they found the grandmother
wandering down 5th.
Okay, well there's one down.
그럼 하나는 해결됐네
I'm getting married today!
나 오늘 결혼한다!
I cracked a rib, but I don't care.
Today's my wedding!
갈비뼈 금갔지만 괜찮아
나 오늘 결혼하니까!
My day is finally here!
마침내 나의 날이 왔도다!
She might not even notice he's gone.
챈들러 없어진 것도
까맣게 모르고...
I'm gonna start getting ready!
준비해야겠다!
준비하도록 놔두면 안 돼
너무 끔찍하다!
We can't let her start getting ready.
This is too awful!
드레스를 입었는데
챈들러가 안 나타나면
She'll be in the gown,
and he won't show up.
Then she'll
have to take off the gown..
그럼 드레스를
벗어야 되고...
Stop it. You can't do this here.
여기서 이러면 안 돼
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
미안해, 미안해
너무 슬퍼서
It's just so sad.
Pull it together.
She can't see you like this.
정신 차려
모니카가 보면 안 돼
- 눈치채면 어떡해
- 나도 알아, 어쩜 좋아!
-She'll know something's wrong.
-I know. I know.
There's no tissue.
티슈가 없네
Can you grab me some toilet paper?
화장지 좀 줄래?
화장지도 떨어졌어
여기 모니카네 화장실 맞아?
Oh, that's gone too.
This is Monica's bathroom, right?
I found one.
- 하나 찾았어
- 잘 됐네
- 여기 있어
- 고마워
Thank you.
어쩜 좋아
Oh, God.
Can I have another one?
하나만 더 줄래?
Sure.
알았어
치실은 안 필요해?
Do you need some floss?
챈들러 안 나타나면
어떻게 되는 거지?
I can't imagine what will happen
if he doesn't show up.
여기 많다
Here's a whole bunch.
결혼식에서 기다리면
She'll be at the wedding waiting...
and people will be whispering,
"That poor girl."
사람들이 "불쌍해라"하며
동정하겠지
Then she'll have to come back here
and live alone.
그리곤 다시 돌아와서
혼자 살아야 될 거고
-Oh, my God.
-What?
- 어머나
- 뭐야?
There was a pregnancy test in the
garbage, and it's positive.
임신 테스트 시약이 있는데
양성이야
Monica's pregnant.
모니카 임신했어
So I guess she won't be totally alone.
완전히 혼자는 아니겠군
다음 편에서는...
Next time on Friends:
- 말해야 돼
- 안 돼, 못 해
-We've gotta tell her.
-No, we can't.
준비하고 있잖아
She's getting ready.
시간 좀 끌어 봐
Can't you stall her?
난 평생 결혼 못할 거야
I'm never gonna get married.
한 장면만 찍으면 되는데
리차드는 프로잖아
We've just got one scene with you two,
and Richard is a pro.
- 취하셨어요?
- 아니!
-Are you drunk?
-No!
취하셨잖아요!
Yes, you are!
그렇다고해
All right.
- 챈들러 어때?
- 좋아
-How's Chandler?
-Great!
- 어디 있어?
- 촬영장에
-Where are you?
-On the set.
최악의 결혼식이
될 거야
It's turning into the worst
wedding ever.